<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>app.clustercut.clustercut</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>ClusterCut</name>
  <summary>Cross-platform Clipboard Sync</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      ClusterCut is a seamless clipboard synchronization tool that works across Linux, macOS and Windows.
      It allows you to copy text on one device and paste it on another instantly, keeping your workflow uninterrupted.
    </p>
    <p>Features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Real-time clipboard synchronization</li>
      <li>Secure peer-to-peer connection</li>
      <li>Clipboard history</li>
      <li>File transfer</li>
      <li>Automatic/Manual transfer mode</li>
      <li>Cross-platform support</li>
      <li>Minimal resource usage</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <developer id="app.clustercut">
    <name>Keith Vassallo</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">app.clustercut.clustercut.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default" xml:lang="en">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/v0.1.1/assets/Screenshots/scr_main.png</image>
      <caption>Main window, showing cluster membership and join details.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/v0.1.1/assets/Screenshots/scr_main_dark.png</image>
      <caption>Main window in dark mode.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/v0.1.1/assets/Screenshots/scr_remote.png</image>
      <caption>Local clusters are automatically discovered, or you can join a remote one over VPN/Internet.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/v0.1.1/assets/Screenshots/scr_history.png</image>
      <caption>Clipboard history allows you to paste and re-send previous clipboard contents.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/v0.1.1/assets/Screenshots/scr_files.png</image>
      <caption>File transfer allows you to send and receive files between devices.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/v0.1.1/assets/Screenshots/scr_settings1.png</image>
      <caption>Use an autogenerated or provisioned cluster name/PIN.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot xml:lang="en">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/v0.1.1/assets/Screenshots/scr_settings2.png</image>
      <caption>Automatic/Manual transfer mode, and auto-download configuration.</caption>
    </screenshot>  
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://clustercut.app</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/keithvassallomt/ClusterCut</url>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#d0eef2</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#1a4a52</color>
  </branding>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="0.4.2" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>No more notification pile-ups when your network changes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Switching Wi-Fi networks, or connecting or disconnecting a VPN, no longer sends you a "device left" notification for every device in your cluster — and a "device joined" for each one as they come back</li>
          <li>Instead, ClusterCut notices your network has changed, quietly keeps looking for your devices in the background, and shows a single "Your network has changed" message</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.1" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>Your cluster now heals itself — devices come back on their own after VPNs, sleep, and network hiccups.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Connect to your cluster over a VPN and your devices appear on their own — no more "Retry Connection" clicks or restarting the app to see everyone</li>
          <li>Devices no longer vanish from the list for no reason, or go missing until you restart — if one is briefly unreachable, ClusterCut quietly keeps checking and brings it back as soon as it responds</li>
          <li>Waking your computer from sleep no longer empties the device list while the network reconnects; and if you wake up on a different network, the list updates to show what's actually reachable there</li>
          <li>A device that joined your cluster while one of your machines was off or away is now recognised automatically when that machine comes back — previously it had to be paired again</li>
          <li>A device you removed from the cluster stays removed, and reconnecting to a device no longer briefly shows a duplicate "Manual" entry</li>
          <li>Bringing the ClusterCut window to the front now quietly refreshes the device list, so what you see is always current</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-07-03">
      <description>
        <p>Big improvements to joining and leaving clusters, plus shared PINs for provisioned clusters.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Provisioned clusters now share a single PIN. When you set up a cluster with a name and PIN, every device that joins picks up that same PIN automatically — you no longer need to set it separately on each device</li>
          <li>You can now join a cluster using the PIN of any device already in it, rather than one specific device. Enter any member's PIN and ClusterCut pairs with the right one; if it doesn't match any device that's online, it asks you to try another device's PIN</li>
          <li>Leaving a cluster is now reliable — the device you leave on disappears from your other devices right away, and removing a device from your cluster works properly too</li>
          <li>When a device leaves and starts a fresh cluster, that new cluster now appears in your nearby list straight away, without having to restart the app</li>
          <li>Fixed a problem where a device could sometimes refuse to join because of leftover records from earlier connection attempts — ClusterCut now clears those out automatically so they don't cause trouble later</li>
          <li>Devices are now identified in a way that rules out two of them ever being mistaken for the same one</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.7" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>A clipboard reliability fix and a calmer diagnostics log.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed large blocks of text occasionally bouncing back and reappearing on the device you copied from, when you copied something else right afterwards</li>
          <li>The Diagnostics event log no longer fills up with routine connection messages at the Minimal level — pairing and any real connection problems still show there, and you can switch to Detailed to see everything</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.6" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>A Windows crash fix, an instant History list for large items, syncing of large blocks of text, and a quieter GNOME notification.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a crash on Windows that could happen when you copied formatted content — such as text from a web page or document — shortly after copying a large amount of text</li>
          <li>Your History list now appears instantly even for very large copied items, like big images or large blocks of text, instead of taking 10–20 seconds. You can also choose how much clipboard content History keeps, under Settings → General</li>
          <li>Large blocks of text (over 10 MB) now sync between your devices and still paste as text on the other side. Text above 100 MB isn't sent, and a note appears in your History instead</li>
          <li>On GNOME, the "clipboard sync is now active" notification no longer pops up every time you start ClusterCut — it now appears only once, after you install or re-enable the extension</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.5" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>A reorganised Settings page, more control on locked-down networks, a live diagnostics view, and tighter handling of your private key and PIN.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Settings is now organised into a sidebar with categories (General, Cluster, Files, Notifications, Diagnostics) instead of one long scrolling page</li>
          <li>Adding a remote device by IP is smarter — if you've paired with it before, it just reconnects; it only asks for a PIN when it's a brand-new device</li>
          <li>New options for restrictive or work networks: you can turn off automatic discovery (mDNS) to stay hidden and connect only by IP, and on Windows you can stop ClusterCut from setting up its firewall rule at startup</li>
          <li>Your cluster's name now stays in sync across all your devices — rename it on one and the others update too, even ones that were offline at the time. Switching back to an auto-generated name asks for confirmation first, since it renames the cluster everywhere</li>
          <li>New diagnostics event log under Settings → Diagnostics: watch pairing and connection activity as it happens, with selectable detail levels and a one-click copy for troubleshooting. It lives only in the app and is never written to a file</li>
          <li>Security: your device's private key and pairing PIN are now saved with locked-down, owner-only permissions; in auto-generated mode the PIN is kept in memory only and never written to disk; and PINs are never written to the log file</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.4" date="2026-05-30">
      <description>
        <p>Clipboard and pairing fixes, plus smoother formatted-text handling on GNOME.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a banner that wrongly told you to re-pair a device when you were connected through a VPN</li>
          <li>Pairing with the wrong PIN now shows a clear "the PIN may be incorrect" message instead of a confusing "session expired" error, and an accidental space in the PIN no longer silently breaks pairing</li>
          <li>Copying formatted text to a Windows PC no longer clears the clipboard on the computer you copied from</li>
          <li>Pasting code copied from PyCharm into Word on Windows now keeps the whole snippet instead of just the last few characters</li>
          <li>A stray space, tab, or blank line on your clipboard is no longer pushed to your other devices</li>
          <li>On GNOME, receiving formatted text now puts the plain text on your clipboard straight away and offers a one-click "Switch to Rich" button in a notification — so pasting into apps like Text Editor, OnlyOffice, or your browser just works</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.3" date="2026-05-27">
      <description>
        <p>Stronger pairing security, an on-demand pause button for pairing, and clearer feedback when a peer is on an older version.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New pairing-pause button in the toolbar — click it to stop accepting new pairing requests when you don't want anyone joining your cluster. The same button also lights up red when pairing has been automatically paused after too many failed attempts in a row</li>
          <li>Pairing security has been further strengthened — a device trying to join your cluster must now prove it knows the right PIN before your device sends any encrypted reply, so someone trying random PINs can no longer gather data from your device to crack them later</li>
          <li>Trying to pair with a device on an older version of ClusterCut now shows the "please upgrade" message right away instead of waiting for the pairing attempt to time out. The amber warning indicator next to a peer's name also now correctly fires for any peer running an older release</li>
          <li>Fixed: the Settings tab was quietly saving the same settings once per second in the background even when nothing had changed</li>
          <li>Pairing new devices requires both sides to be on 0.3.3 or later — already-paired devices continue to work as before, even if some are still on older versions</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.2" date="2026-05-23">
      <description>
        <p>Easier pairing over VPN / restrictive networks, a clearer PIN, and a one-click history wipe.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>"Add Remote Peer" now actually works when local discovery is blocked (e.g. you're connecting over a VPN, or your firewall is filtering multicast). Type the peer's IP and you'll be asked for its PIN — same as pairing a device you found nearby</li>
          <li>Your own PIN is now hidden behind dots on the main screen by default, with a new eye button next to the copy button to reveal it. The copy button still works whether it's revealed or not — handy if you're showing your screen to someone</li>
          <li>The PIN label is now "My Cluster PIN" and Settings explains that each device keeps its own PIN; pairing never shares it</li>
          <li>New "Clear" button on the Clipboard History view wipes every entry from this device in one go, with a confirmation. Other devices in the cluster keep their own history</li>
          <li>Fixed: after joining a cluster you no longer briefly appear in the peer list as a peer of yourself</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.1" date="2026-05-16">
      <description>
        <p>Stronger pairing security and clearer handling of failed pairing attempts.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Pairing security has been strengthened — someone else on your network can no longer interfere with the pairing handshake, even if they observe the messages going back and forth</li>
          <li>After several failed pairing attempts in a row, your device pauses incoming pairing and shows a notification so you can re-enable it when you're ready</li>
          <li>New "Verbose pairing logs" option under Settings → Diagnostics, useful if you ever need to troubleshoot why a pairing isn't completing</li>
          <li>All your devices need to be on 0.3.1 or later — devices running 0.3.0 cannot talk to this release</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-05-10">
      <description>
        <p>Image and rich-text clipboard sync, plus stronger security.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Image clipboard sync — copy a picture (from a browser, a screenshot tool, etc.) and it's ready to paste on your other devices, into any app</li>
          <li>Rich-text clipboard sync — formatting from Word, Pages, your browser, Apple Mail and similar apps now comes across to your other devices intact</li>
          <li>Pairing and clipboard traffic have been redesigned for stronger security</li>
          <li>If a device in your cluster is running a version too old to keep up, ClusterCut now flags which one and prompts you to upgrade</li>
          <li>Clipboard history now scrolls properly when the list gets long</li>
          <li>Windows reliability — images paste cleanly into apps like Paint and Word, notifications about new devices and incoming files no longer get dropped, and the firewall rule now covers everything ClusterCut needs</li>
          <li>macOS Pages now preserves formatting when pasting rich text received from another device</li>
          <li>All your devices need to be on 0.3.0 or later — older versions cannot talk to this release</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.3" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Faster file transfers and tighter privacy for LAN-only setups.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Optional file transfer compression — speeds up sending large text, code, or log files. Off by default; turn it on under Settings → File Transfer once all your devices are on 0.2.3 or later, since older versions can't read compressed transfers</li>
          <li>ClusterCut no longer fetches fonts from the internet at startup, keeping the app fully self-contained on your local network</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.2" date="2026-04-19">
      <description>
        <p>Better GNOME Wayland support and clearer status reporting.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>File copies now sync on GNOME Wayland — copy a file in Nautilus, paste it on another peer</li>
          <li>Clipboard sync starts automatically as soon as the ClusterCut GNOME extension is enabled; no app restart needed</li>
          <li>Notifications now tell you when clipboard sync can't start (missing or outdated extension) or has been paused</li>
          <li>Current sync mode is shown in GNOME's Background Apps list, matching the Quick Settings toggle</li>
          <li>Requires ClusterCut GNOME extension v3.0 or newer</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.1" date="2026-04-05">
      <description>
        <p>Fewer spurious notifications and better handling of suspend/resume and Wi-Fi changes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Far fewer false "Device Joined" / "Device Left" notifications after sleep/wake or reconnecting to Wi-Fi</li>
          <li>Peers on a previous network are now cleaned up silently when the local IP changes</li>
          <li>Windows: the firewall rule check avoids the repeated UAC prompt on every launch</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-03-25">
      <description>
        <p>Clipboard sync now works natively on Wayland. No more X11 workarounds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Full Wayland support for KDE Plasma, Sway, and Hyprland</li>
          <li>GNOME Wayland support via the ClusterCut extension (install from GNOME Extensions)</li>
          <li>Updated GNOME extension to v2.0 with clipboard bridging</li>
          <li>Flatpak runtime updated to GNOME 50</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.8" date="2026-03-25">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Flatpak: added X11 socket for clipboard support on Wayland (via XWayland)</li>
          <li>Tray icon now visible on KDE/Plasma dark panels (symbolic icon override is limited to GNOME-like desktops)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.7" date="2026-03-18">
      <description>
        <p>Updated Flatpak permission requests.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.6" date="2026-02-24">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed tray icon appearance on non-Flatpak Linux installs</li>
          <li>Improved appearance of Flathub app page</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.5" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Notifications now use the Notification portal for better Flatpak integration</li>
          <li>Fixed autostart command being double-wrapped by the Background portal</li>
          <li>Fixed window being invisible when starting minimized and then showing from tray</li>
          <li>License changed to GPL-3.0-or-later</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.4" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <p>Autostart now uses the Background portal for better integration with Flatpak and GNOME.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.3" date="2026-02-20">
      <description>
        <p>Tray icon now uses a GNOME symbolic style with badge support for a more native look.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.2" date="2026-02-19">
      <description>
        <p>Flatpak packaging improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.1" date="2026-02-19">
      <description>
        <p>Device join and leave notifications are now more reliable.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
